BEN GRAHAM: This is probably the second most important thing, especially when you are playing the field in the game of baseball.
This is a glove.
This, right here, is your standard outfielder's glove.
Gloves do come in various sizes and various forms, depending on the position that you're going to play.
Gloves are made up of just a very few basic things.
It's usually made out of leather or synthetic leather, woven together with leather threads.
This is the pocket right here.
This is where you ideally want to catch the ball.
You'll hear people--as you work your glove you want to create a deep, nice pocket and cushion.
If you catch the ball in the pocket, it's not going to sting your hand, and, trust me, if you catch it here in the heel, it does hurt.
It's also very difficult to catch in the heel because sometimes the ball will pop out.
Also, some gloves have a finger-hole opener right here.
It doesn't really affect the game at all.
Some people feel just more comfortable and like to have more control over how they catch the ball if their finger is on the outside.
Now, if we were to take an infielder's glove, you'd take a couple of inches off of the end of this glove right here.
An infielder's glove is much smaller.
It's because they're used to field the ball on the ground, so you want less size.
In the outfield, you need a bigger pocket, a little bit thicker.
Now, the first baseman's glove is the exact opposite.
It's larger than your standard outfielder's glove.
It has a larger pocket so that the first baseman can stretch and pull the ball in more easily.
The catcher's mitt is smaller but thicker with more padding, which allows the--it protects the catcher's hand as the pitcher is throwing.
In the Major League level, pitchers are throwing in the mid to upper 90s with regularity, so you want a thick pad for your catcher's mitt.
But any glove will do for any position; some are just better suited than others.
And that's all about the glove.